# Calvin Chun-yu Chan

<u>hello@calvincchan.com</u> • 604-356-2406 Vancouver, British Columbia, Canada Web: <u>calvincchan.com</u> Github: <u>github.com/calvincchan</u> Linkedin: <u>linkedin.com/in/calvincchan</u>



## **PROFILE**

As an experienced full-stack developer who has been working on startup projects for the last 10 years, I have a track record of delivering fully functional products with limited resources, ever-changing requirements, and a continuously evolving tech stack. For the most part, I have worked solo or with a handful of team members. I am happy to accept challenges and venture into areas I am not familiar with.

#### **SKILLS**

ES6 • Typescript • NodeJS • ExpressJS • Fastify • Supabase • ReactJS • MongoDB • PostgreSQL • Docker

## **EXPERIENCE**

#### **Full Stack Developer**

# **EDU.INK Limited, Hong Kong**

Jun 2019 - Present

- Designed the system architecture of multiple products including student information system, billing, admission and enrolment, online payment, library, parent-teacher CMS, live chat system, and mobile app.
- Transitioned from a single monolithic PHP app to modularized NodeJS/MongoDB based API servers, web
  console, and mobile client apps, resulting in improved scalability, functionality, and efficiency for endusers and stakeholders.
- <u>Backend</u>: NodeJS, MongoDB, PostgreSQL, Redis, Typescript, Jest, Docker. Fastify for the API framework. Bull for job queuing. OpenAPI for documentation and API input validation and serialization. SocketIO for chat.
- 3rd party integrations: Powerschool, eTapestry, Active Directory, Stripe, OneSignal, S3, Google Cloud.
- Frontend & mobile app: VueJS, ReactJS, React Native.
- CI & Infrastructure: CircleCI, BitBucket Pipeline, AWS EC2, Digital Ocean Docker App platform.

# **Full Stack Developer**

# **GUZZU**, Hong Kong

Jun 2017 - Sep 2019

- Developed and deployed an e-commerce platform catering to small expat merchants in China. Created
  an array of products such as inventory management system, shopping applications for web and mobile,
  WeChat integration, online payment gateway, customizable storefront, and e-ticket issuance and
  redemption system.
- <u>Backend</u>: NodeJS, MongoDB, Redis. <u>Frontend</u>: AngularJS, WeChat Mini Program SDK.

## **Full Stack Developer**

## **Giftpass Limited, Hong Kong**

Mar 2013 - Jun 2017

- As a part of a China Accelerator Startup Project, I designed and implemented a digital gift voucher platform that streamlined the process for consumers, merchants.
- Backend: NodeJS, MongoDB, Apple Wallet SDK. Frontend: AngularJS.

## UX Designer Genesix Inc., Japan May 2011 - Jul 2012

Designed user experience, interface, and visual design for iOS app targeting Japanese market.
 Collaborated with development team to create intuitive interfaces and visually appealing graphics that received positive feedback from users and increased downloads and engagement.

# **Web Designer and Engineer**

## A.C.O. Inc., Japan

Sep 2010 - Mar 2011

- Created websites for international clients using web design, rapid prototyping, and UI engineering skills with technologies like Fireworks and JQuery.
- Developed a Facebook Page and social application for global marketing initiatives that successfully increased brand awareness and user engagement.

#### **Software Developer**

## The University of British Columbia, Canada

Mar 2007 - Jun 2010

- Designed and implemented a search engine and management system for international innateimmunology experiments (<u>innatedb.ca</u>), incorporating data visualization and report generation capabilities.
- Developed intuitive UI for the management systems that facilitated ease of use and efficient data management.

## **Software Developer**

# **Active Logic Inc., Canada**

Jun 2006 - Feb 2007

• Developed customer management system for a gaming platform.

## **Software Engineer &**

## **System Administrator**

## ehosting.ca, Canada

May 2003 - Aug 2005

• Performed customer management software development, hosting product development, Linux server administration, and MySQL database management.

### **EDUCATION**

University of British Columbia — B.Sc., Computer Science, 2000 - 2003